<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/preview/pr-56/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/preview/pr-56/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-13T15:33:01+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-56/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Rokita Lab</title><entry><title type="html">Dr. Chao Di joins the Rokita Lab and Brain Tumor Institute Bioinformatics Core!</title><link href="/preview/pr-56/2025/05/12/welcome-chao.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dr. Chao Di joins the Rokita Lab and Brain Tumor Institute Bioinformatics Core!" /><published>2025-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T15:28:43+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-56/2025/05/12/welcome-chao</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-56/2025/05/12/welcome-chao.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to welcome Dr. Chao Di as a Senior Bioinformatics Engineer and Scientist in the Rokita Lab and the Brain Tumor Institute Bioinformatics Core at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.</p>

<p>Chao brings more than a decade of experience developing computational methods and production-scale pipelines for multi-omics analysis across academic, clinical, and industry settings. 
Most recently, Chao was a Senior Computational Biology Scientist at Spark Therapeutics (Roche Group), where he developed an internal AAV vector integration analysis platform to evaluate insertion risks in gene therapy programs, optimized single-nucleus RNA-seq analysis for rare cell types, and led long-read sequencing and spatial profiling workflows.</p>

<p>Before his time in industry, Chao worked at the Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia (CHOP) and the University of Pennsylvania, where he contributed to high-impact studies in immunology, cancer biology, infectious diseases, and neurodegeneration. 
His toolkit spans cutting-edge transcriptomics and proteomics platforms including XLIP-Seq, 4sU-Seq, ChIP-Seq, scRNA-Seq, CyTOF, and Olink — all supported by deep experience in pipeline development with Snakemake, Nextflow, Python, R, and cloud/HPC environments.
Earlier in his career, he helped build CLIPdb and contributed to foundational ENCODE efforts on RNA-binding proteins and long non-coding RNAs.</p>

<p>Chao is passionate about applying data science and engineering to tackle big data challenges in biomedical research. He thrives at the intersection of biology and computation, building scalable pipelines and analytical frameworks to extract insights from single-cell, spatial, and multi-omics datasets. At CNH, he’s excited to collaborate across teams to transform complex data into actionable discoveries for pediatric care.</p>

<p>We’re thrilled to have Chao on board as we continue building a robust analytical infrastructure to drive discovery and precision medicine in pediatric brain tumor research here at Children’s.
Welcome, Chao! 👏</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to welcome Dr. Chao Di as a Senior Bioinformatics Engineer and Scientist in the Rokita Lab and the Brain Tumor Institute Bioinformatics Core at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dr. Patricia Sullivan joins the Rokita Lab!</title><link href="/preview/pr-56/2025/05/12/welcome-patricia.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dr. Patricia Sullivan joins the Rokita Lab!" /><published>2025-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T15:28:43+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-56/2025/05/12/welcome-patricia</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-56/2025/05/12/welcome-patricia.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to announce the arrival of Dr. Patricia Sullivan as a Bioinformatics Scientist in the Rokita Lab at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.
Patricia joins us from the Children’s Cancer Institute in Sydney, where she became a leading expert in splice-altering variation in pediatric cancer and rare disease genomics.</p>

<p>Patricia brings deep expertise in splice variant interpretation.
She played a leading role in the development of multiple computational tools to improve splice variant prediction: <a href="https://github.com/CCICB/introme">Introme</a> for impact prediction and <a href="https://compbio.ccia.org.au/splicevardb/">SpliceVarDB</a> to mine and visualize experimentally validated human splice variants (<a href="https://github.com/CCICB/SpliceVarDB">codebase here</a>). 
As a Fulbright Scholar at the Broad Institute, Patricia collaborated closely with variant curation experts from the Rare Genomes Project and ClinGen to improve the interpretation of splice-altering variants—critical work that supports more accurate pathogenicity classifications in clinical genomics and precision medicine.</p>

<p>Patricia is passionate about using genetic data to close diagnostic gaps and help more people access precision therapies. She is especially interested in complex or atypical genetic variation, with the goal of ensuring that individuals who are often missed by standard testing can receive accurate diagnoses and appropriate care.</p>

<p>We’re thrilled to have Patricia join our team as we continue to build tools and uncover biological insights that advance precision medicine for children with brain tumors.
Welcome, Patricia! 👏</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to announce the arrival of Dr. Patricia Sullivan as a Bioinformatics Scientist in the Rokita Lab at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉. Patricia joins us from the Children’s Cancer Institute in Sydney, where she became a leading expert in splice-altering variation in pediatric cancer and rare disease genomics.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dr. Jessica Daggett joins the Brain Tumor Institute Bioinformatics Core!</title><link href="/preview/pr-56/2025/03/31/welcome-jessica.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dr. Jessica Daggett joins the Brain Tumor Institute Bioinformatics Core!" /><published>2025-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T15:28:43+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-56/2025/03/31/welcome-jessica</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-56/2025/03/31/welcome-jessica.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are happy to announce our recruitment of Dr. Jessica Daggett as a Bioinformatics Scientist in the Brain Tumor Institute (BTI) Bioinformatics Core at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.</p>

<p>Jessica joins us from Syngenta Biologicals, where she led development of genomic data pipelines and visualization tools to support high-throughput genome screening in R&amp;D. 
As a technical expert in the Crop Protection Bioinformatics Strategy Team, she created solutions for FAIR data integration and scalable genomic infrastructure.</p>

<p>We are excited to have Jessica join our team to further our mission of finding cures for children with pediatric brain and spinal cord tumors. 
Her experience in genome architecture, tool development, interactive dashboards, and cross-disciplinary collaboration will be a tremendous asset to the BTI.
Welcome, Jessica! 👏</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are happy to announce our recruitment of Dr. Jessica Daggett as a Bioinformatics Scientist in the Brain Tumor Institute (BTI) Bioinformatics Core at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dr. Kaylyn Clark joins the Rokita Lab and Brain Tumor Institute!</title><link href="/preview/pr-56/2025/03/17/welcome-kaylyn.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dr. Kaylyn Clark joins the Rokita Lab and Brain Tumor Institute!" /><published>2025-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T15:28:43+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-56/2025/03/17/welcome-kaylyn</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-56/2025/03/17/welcome-kaylyn.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are happy to announce our recruitment of Dr. Kaylyn Clark as a Postdoctoral Fellow in the Rokita Lab and Brain Tumor Institute (BTI) at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.</p>

<p>Kaylyn recently completed her Ph.D. in Genomics and Computational Biology from the University of Pennsylvania, during which she studied the genetic basis of Alzheimer’s Disease (AD) using statistical and genetic modeling in genome-wide association studies (GWAS) utilizing polygenic risk scores (PRS).
To further study the polygenic architecture of AD, Kaylyn co-developed a joint genetic score called MetaGRS.</p>

<p>We are excited to have Kaylyn joining our team as we further study the germline and somatic basis of pediatric high-grade gliomas which form in patients with the tumor syndrome, Neurofibromatosis.
Welcome, Kaylyn! 👏</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are happy to announce our recruitment of Dr. Kaylyn Clark as a Postdoctoral Fellow in the Rokita Lab and Brain Tumor Institute (BTI) at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New collaborative manuscript exploring germline pathogenic variation in pediatric DMGs published!</title><link href="/preview/pr-56/2025/03/12/germline-dmg-paper.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New collaborative manuscript exploring germline pathogenic variation in pediatric DMGs published!" /><published>2025-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T15:28:43+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-56/2025/03/12/germline-dmg-paper</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-56/2025/03/12/germline-dmg-paper.html"><![CDATA[<p>We were thrilled to contribute to the recent publication, “Germline analysis of an international cohort of pediatric diffuse midline glioma patients”, led by collaborator Dr. Marion Mateos.
In this project, we assessed pathogenicity of germline variants driving DIPG and DMG.
Read more about it <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40072012/">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We were thrilled to contribute to the recent publication, “Germline analysis of an international cohort of pediatric diffuse midline glioma patients”, led by collaborator Dr. Marion Mateos. In this project, we assessed pathogenicity of germline variants driving DIPG and DMG. Read more about it here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dr. Bicna Song joins the Brain Tumor Institute Bioinformatics Core!</title><link href="/preview/pr-56/2025/03/04/welcome-bicna-s.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dr. Bicna Song joins the Brain Tumor Institute Bioinformatics Core!" /><published>2025-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T15:28:43+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-56/2025/03/04/welcome-bicna-s</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-56/2025/03/04/welcome-bicna-s.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are happy to announce our recruitment of Dr. Bicna Song as a Bioinformatics Scientist in the Brain Tumor Institute (BTI) Bioinformatics Core at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.</p>

<p>Bicna joins us after a very successful postdoctoral fellowship with Dr. Wei Li at CNH, where she developed expertise in transcriptomic data analysis, including bulk RNA-Seq, single-cell RNA-Seq, and Perturb-Seq. 
Her innovative work led to the creation of the Perturbation-Response Score (PS), a novel method to quantify how individual cells respond to genetic perturbations at single-cell resolution, providing powerful insights into cellular heterogeneity and gene function.</p>

<p>We are excited for Bicna to bring her expertise to the BTI Bioinformatics Core, where she will contribute to advancing precision medicine for pediatric brain tumors. 
Her deep knowledge in computational transcriptional biology and data-driven discovery will be invaluable to our mission.
Welcome, Bicna! 👏</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are happy to announce our recruitment of Dr. Bicna Song as a Bioinformatics Scientist in the Brain Tumor Institute (BTI) Bioinformatics Core at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New press release - Q&amp;amp;A with Dr. Rokita: Building Bioinformatics Infrastructure at the Brain Tumor Institute</title><link href="/preview/pr-56/2025/02/26/rokita-q-and-a-bti.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New press release - Q&amp;amp;A with Dr. Rokita: Building Bioinformatics Infrastructure at the Brain Tumor Institute" /><published>2025-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T15:28:43+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-56/2025/02/26/rokita-q-and-a-bti</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-56/2025/02/26/rokita-q-and-a-bti.html"><![CDATA[<p>Dr. Rokita recently sat down with the press team at Children’s National to discuss her laboratory’s research, the development of the Brain Tumor Institute (BTI) Bioinformatics Core, and her collaborative and open science vision for the future. Read all about it <a href="https://innovationdistrict.childrensnational.org/building-bioinformatics-infrastructure-at-the-brain-tumor-institute/">here</a>!</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="media" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dr. Rokita recently sat down with the press team at Children’s National to discuss her laboratory’s research, the development of the Brain Tumor Institute (BTI) Bioinformatics Core, and her collaborative and open science vision for the future. Read all about it here!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New tumor predisposition syndrome described!</title><link href="/preview/pr-56/2025/02/24/drosha-paper.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New tumor predisposition syndrome described!" /><published>2025-02-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T15:28:43+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-56/2025/02/24/drosha-paper</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-56/2025/02/24/drosha-paper.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are happy to announce the publication of “Germline pathogenic DROSHA variants are linked to pineoblastoma and Wilms tumor predisposition”, an international collaboration in which we describe a new tumor syndrome characterized by pathogenic germline <em>DROSHA</em> variants. Read more about it <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39992227/">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are happy to announce the publication of “Germline pathogenic DROSHA variants are linked to pineoblastoma and Wilms tumor predisposition”, an international collaboration in which we describe a new tumor syndrome characterized by pathogenic germline DROSHA variants. Read more about it here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alex Sickler joins the Rokita Lab!</title><link href="/preview/pr-56/2025/02/18/welcome-alex-s.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alex Sickler joins the Rokita Lab!" /><published>2025-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T15:28:43+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-56/2025/02/18/welcome-alex-s</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-56/2025/02/18/welcome-alex-s.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are thrilled to welcome Alex Sickler as a Bioinformatics Engineer in the Rokita Lab and Brain Tumor Institute (BTI) Bioinformatics Core at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉. 
Alex joins us after many productive years of bioinformatics engineering and infrastructure management work at GeneDx, the National Cancer Institute, and the Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia (CHOP).</p>

<p>While at CHOP, Alex played a critical role in scaling modules from the <a href="https://github.com/rokitalab/OpenPedCan-Project">Open Pediatric Cancer (OpenPedCan) Project</a> and has contributed to the development of the <a href="https://github.com/kids-first/kf-dev-single-cell-rna">Kids First single-cell and single-nuclei RNA-Seq workflows</a>.
Additionally, he led implementation of automated data ingest workflows and applications for the Kids First Data Resource Center.</p>

<p>We’re excited to have Alex join us at CNH as we build our BTI Bioinformatics Core, contributing to our mission of advancing precision medicine for pediatric brain tumors. 
Welcome, Alex! 👏</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are thrilled to welcome Alex Sickler as a Bioinformatics Engineer in the Rokita Lab and Brain Tumor Institute (BTI) Bioinformatics Core at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉. Alex joins us after many productive years of bioinformatics engineering and infrastructure management work at GeneDx, the National Cancer Institute, and the Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia (CHOP).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Manuscript describing molecular features of low-grade glioma imaging clusters published!</title><link href="/preview/pr-56/2025/02/14/lgg-imaging-paper.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Manuscript describing molecular features of low-grade glioma imaging clusters published!" /><published>2025-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T15:28:43+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-56/2025/02/14/lgg-imaging-paper</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-56/2025/02/14/lgg-imaging-paper.html"><![CDATA[<p>We were thrilled to be a part of the recent publication, “Imaging Clusters of Pediatric Low-Grade Glioma are Associated with Distinct Molecular Characteristics”, led by our collaborator <a href="https://d3b.center/team-members/anahita-fathi-kazerooni/">Dr. Anahita Fathi Kazerooni</a>. Read more about it <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39952665/">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We were thrilled to be a part of the recent publication, “Imaging Clusters of Pediatric Low-Grade Glioma are Associated with Distinct Molecular Characteristics”, led by our collaborator Dr. Anahita Fathi Kazerooni. Read more about it here.]]></summary></entry></feed>