<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/preview/pr-92/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/preview/pr-92/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-01-13T19:47:38+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-92/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Rokita Lab</title><entry><title type="html">Jacob White joins the Rokita Lab!</title><link href="/preview/pr-92/2026/01/06/welcome-jacob.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jacob White joins the Rokita Lab!" /><published>2026-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-13T19:46:21+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-92/2026/01/06/welcome-jacob</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-92/2026/01/06/welcome-jacob.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to welcome masters student, Jacob White, to the Rokita Lab at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.
Jacob will begin his research by studying both mechanisms of RNA splicing in pediatric brain tumors and identifying tractable splice-derived therapeutic targets.</p>

<p>Jacob is passionate about using multi-omics data to improve therapeutics.</p>

<p>Welcome, Jacob! 👏</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to welcome masters student, Jacob White, to the Rokita Lab at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉. Jacob will begin his research by studying both mechanisms of RNA splicing in pediatric brain tumors and identifying tractable splice-derived therapeutic targets.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Our integrative analysis of PBTA host-tumor genomes has been published in Nature Communications!</title><link href="/preview/pr-92/2025/11/21/corbett-germline-paper-accepted.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our integrative analysis of PBTA host-tumor genomes has been published in Nature Communications!" /><published>2025-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-13T19:46:21+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-92/2025/11/21/corbett-germline-paper-accepted</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-92/2025/11/21/corbett-germline-paper-accepted.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re thrilled to share the publication of our latest study, “Germline pathogenic variation impacts somatic alterations and patient outcomes in pediatric central nervous system tumors,” now out in <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-65190-4">Nature Communications</a>. Led by <a href="https://rokitalab.com/members/02-ryan-corbett.html">Dr. Ryan Corbett</a> in the Rokita Lab, this work represents a comprehensive multi-omic analysis of germline and somatic data from 830 pediatric brain tumor patients in the #PBTA — truly a <em>tour de force</em> by the team.</p>

<p>We highlight the importance of germline testing at diagnosis, identifying rare germline pathogenic (P) or likely pathogenic (LP) variants in 48 patients (5.7%) who had no clinically reported cancer predisposition syndrome. 
Among all P/LP carriers, 34.6% had putative somatic second hits or loss-of-function tumor alterations, consistent with classical tumor suppressor models.
We link germline P/LP variation with somatic events, tumor histologies, molecular subtypes, and clinical outcomes — with some variants associated with protection and others with poorer survival.
Together, these findings deepen our understanding of how inherited or early-life genetic changes shape pediatric CNS tumor development, behavior, and outcomes. 
They pave the way for improved diagnosis, risk stratification, monitoring, and targeted therapy.</p>

<p>🙏 Enormous thanks to our collaborators Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia — especially my partner-in-crime Sharon Diskin and co-first author Rebecca Kaufman. 
Thank you to our clinical experts whose insights into gene lists and variant curation were invaluable: Miriam Bornhorst, Suzanne MacFarland, Kristina Cole, and Shelly McQuaid.</p>

<p>Special thanks to the patients and families, the Children’s Brain Tumor Network for creating this dataset, the anonymous donors to the Brain Tumor Institute, Gabriella Miller Kids First Data Resource Center for supporting us with cloud credits, and every member of the team whose dedication made this possible.</p>

<p>Read the Children’s National press release <a href="https://innovationdistrict.childrensnational.org/new-insights-into-genetics-of-childhood-brain-and-spinal-tumors/">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re thrilled to share the publication of our latest study, “Germline pathogenic variation impacts somatic alterations and patient outcomes in pediatric central nervous system tumors,” now out in Nature Communications. Led by Dr. Ryan Corbett in the Rokita Lab, this work represents a comprehensive multi-omic analysis of germline and somatic data from 830 pediatric brain tumor patients in the #PBTA — truly a tour de force by the team.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dr. Meghali Goswami joins the Rokita Lab!</title><link href="/preview/pr-92/2025/10/13/welcome-meg.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dr. Meghali Goswami joins the Rokita Lab!" /><published>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-13T19:46:21+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-92/2025/10/13/welcome-meg</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-92/2025/10/13/welcome-meg.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to welcome Dr. Meghali (Meg) Goswami as a Staff Scientist in the Rokita Lab at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.
Meg joins us from the National Cancer Institute, where she became a leading expert in tumor immunology, translational research, and biomarker discovery for immuno-oncology therapies.</p>

<p>At NCI, Meg designed and led independent research focused on identifying immunological correlates of clinical response and survival in patients with solid tumors treated with investigational immunotherapies in phase I/II clinical trials. Her work leveraged high-dimensional flow cytometry, multi-omic analyses, and machine learning to uncover novel mechanisms of immune modulation and predictive biomarkers of treatment response.</p>

<p>Meg is passionate about integrating immunology, genomics, and data-driven discovery to develop immunotherapies for the treatment of cancer. She is also committed to building welcoming and inclusive communities that foster growth, collaborations, and friendships.</p>

<p>We’re thrilled to have you on the team, Meg, as we bring our computational discoveries to the bench, preclinically validating new therapeutic targets to advance precision medicine for children with brain tumors.
Welcome, Meg! 👏</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to welcome Dr. Meghali (Meg) Goswami as a Staff Scientist in the Rokita Lab at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉. Meg joins us from the National Cancer Institute, where she became a leading expert in tumor immunology, translational research, and biomarker discovery for immuno-oncology therapies.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dr. Shang-Yang (Sam) Chen joins the Brain Tumor Institute Bioinformatics Core!</title><link href="/preview/pr-92/2025/10/13/welcome-sam.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dr. Shang-Yang (Sam) Chen joins the Brain Tumor Institute Bioinformatics Core!" /><published>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-13T19:46:21+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-92/2025/10/13/welcome-sam</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-92/2025/10/13/welcome-sam.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to welcome Dr. Shang-Yang (Sam) Chen as a Bioinformatics Scientist in the Brain Tumor Institute Bioinformatics Core at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.</p>

<p>Sam brings extensive experience in developing analytical workflows and integrating multi-omics datasets across industry and academic research settings. Most recently, he was a Bioinformatics Scientist at Dyno Therapeutics, where he designed and executed production-scale single-nucleus RNA-seq (snRNA-seq) quality control and analytical pipelines. He also led efforts to evaluate and validate machine guided AAV gene-therapy vectors, contributing directly to two successful product launches.</p>

<p>We’re thrilled to have Sam on board as we continue building a robust analytical infrastructure to drive discovery and precision medicine in pediatric research here at Children’s.
Welcome, Sam! 👏</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to welcome Dr. Shang-Yang (Sam) Chen as a Bioinformatics Scientist in the Brain Tumor Institute Bioinformatics Core at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dr. Corbett named as 2025 CCF NextGen Awardee!</title><link href="/preview/pr-92/2025/08/07/corbett-ccf.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dr. Corbett named as 2025 CCF NextGen Awardee!" /><published>2025-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-13T19:46:21+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-92/2025/08/07/corbett-ccf</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-92/2025/08/07/corbett-ccf.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are thrilled to announce that Dr. Ryan Corbett has been selected as the 2025 NextGen Awardee by the Children’s Cancer Foundation for his grant entitled, “Identification and functional targeting of alternative splice site usage in pediatric high-grade gliomas”.</p>

<p>The NextGen award is given annually to one young investigator dedicated to a long-term career in pediatric oncology research.
To read the CCF press release, see <a href="https://childrenscancerfoundation.org/2025awardees/">here</a></p>

<p>We are extra proud of this award, as it is the first Rokita Lab grant originating at Children’s National!
Thank you to Giant Food’s Pediatric Cancer Fundraising Campaign and the Children’s Cancer Foundation!</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are thrilled to announce that Dr. Ryan Corbett has been selected as the 2025 NextGen Awardee by the Children’s Cancer Foundation for his grant entitled, “Identification and functional targeting of alternative splice site usage in pediatric high-grade gliomas”.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Akhil Chada joins the Rokita Lab!</title><link href="/preview/pr-92/2025/07/08/welcome-akhil.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Akhil Chada joins the Rokita Lab!" /><published>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-13T19:46:21+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-92/2025/07/08/welcome-akhil</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-92/2025/07/08/welcome-akhil.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to welcome Akhil Chada to the Rokita Lab at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.
Akhil joins us as a summer student and rising high school senior at James Madison High School in Fairfax County, Virginia. 
He brings expertise in several coding languages (Python, C++, R, and Java) and advanced mathematics.</p>

<p>Akhil is passionate about research at the intersection of math and biology, and is especially excited to apply these skills to the biomedical world to create real impact.</p>

<p>We’re thrilled to have Akhil with us as we delve into predictive algorithms to target RNA splicing in pediatric brain tumors!</p>

<p>Welcome, Akhil! 👏</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to welcome Akhil Chada to the Rokita Lab at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉. Akhil joins us as a summer student and rising high school senior at James Madison High School in Fairfax County, Virginia. He brings expertise in several coding languages (Python, C++, R, and Java) and advanced mathematics.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Open Pediatric Cancer manuscript has been accepted for publication!</title><link href="/preview/pr-92/2025/07/04/opc-paper-accepted.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Open Pediatric Cancer manuscript has been accepted for publication!" /><published>2025-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-13T19:46:21+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-92/2025/07/04/opc-paper-accepted</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-92/2025/07/04/opc-paper-accepted.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to announce that our large, collaborative work on the Open Pediatric Cancer (OpenPedCan) Project has been accepted in GigaScience!
We are very grateful for the many researchers, clinicians, engineers, bioinformaticians, and investigators who have contributed to this work – a true team effort!
Read the preprint <a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2024.07.09.599086v3">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to announce that our large, collaborative work on the Open Pediatric Cancer (OpenPedCan) Project has been accepted in GigaScience! We are very grateful for the many researchers, clinicians, engineers, bioinformaticians, and investigators who have contributed to this work – a true team effort! Read the preprint here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New collaborative manuscript identifying and testing a splice event in the NRCAM gene has been accepted in Cell Reports!</title><link href="/preview/pr-92/2025/07/01/nrcam-paper-accepted.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New collaborative manuscript identifying and testing a splice event in the NRCAM gene has been accepted in Cell Reports!" /><published>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-13T19:46:21+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-92/2025/07/01/nrcam-paper-accepted</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-92/2025/07/01/nrcam-paper-accepted.html"><![CDATA[<p>We were thrilled to contribute to the recently accepted manuscript, “<em>NRCAM</em> variant defined by microexon skipping is an essential, antigenically distinct, and targetable surface proteoform in high-grade gliomas”, led by the lab of collaborator Dr. Andrei Thomas-Tikhonenko.
In this project, we identified a tumor-specific exon inclusion event in the <em>NRCAM</em> gene as a new therapeutic target.
Read the preprint <a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2025.01.09.631916v4">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="publication" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We were thrilled to contribute to the recently accepted manuscript, “NRCAM variant defined by microexon skipping is an essential, antigenically distinct, and targetable surface proteoform in high-grade gliomas”, led by the lab of collaborator Dr. Andrei Thomas-Tikhonenko. In this project, we identified a tumor-specific exon inclusion event in the NRCAM gene as a new therapeutic target. Read the preprint here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Aylar Babaei joins the BTI Bioinformatics Core!</title><link href="/preview/pr-92/2025/06/02/welcome-aylar.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Aylar Babaei joins the BTI Bioinformatics Core!" /><published>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-13T19:46:21+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-92/2025/06/02/welcome-aylar</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-92/2025/06/02/welcome-aylar.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are thrilled to announce Aylar Babaei as a Bioinformatics Scientist in the BTI Bioinformatics Core at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.
Aylar joins the Core after a productive year right here at CNH, where she contributed to multiple computational workflows, including Ribo-seq analysis, HLA typing, and MHC class I epitope prediction. 
She brings hands-on experience running large-scale pipelines on the high-performance computing (HPC) environment.</p>

<p>Aylar is passionate about understanding research workflows, identifying challenges, and developing practical solutions that connect technical work to real-world healthcare impact.</p>

<p>We’re very happy to have Aylar officially join our team as we continue building infrastructure and tools to support BTI investigators and collaborators.</p>

<p>Welcome, Aylar! 👏</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are thrilled to announce Aylar Babaei as a Bioinformatics Scientist in the BTI Bioinformatics Core at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉. Aylar joins the Core after a productive year right here at CNH, where she contributed to multiple computational workflows, including Ribo-seq analysis, HLA typing, and MHC class I epitope prediction. She brings hands-on experience running large-scale pipelines on the high-performance computing (HPC) environment.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dr. Chao Di joins the Rokita Lab and Brain Tumor Institute Bioinformatics Core!</title><link href="/preview/pr-92/2025/05/12/welcome-chao.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dr. Chao Di joins the Rokita Lab and Brain Tumor Institute Bioinformatics Core!" /><published>2025-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-13T19:46:21+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-92/2025/05/12/welcome-chao</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-92/2025/05/12/welcome-chao.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to welcome Dr. Chao Di as a Senior Bioinformatics Engineer and Scientist in the Rokita Lab and the Brain Tumor Institute Bioinformatics Core at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.</p>

<p>Chao brings more than a decade of experience developing computational methods and production-scale pipelines for multi-omics analysis across academic, clinical, and industry settings. 
Most recently, Chao was a Senior Computational Biology Scientist at Spark Therapeutics (Roche Group), where he developed an internal AAV vector integration analysis platform to evaluate insertion risks in gene therapy programs, optimized single-nucleus RNA-seq analysis for rare cell types, and led long-read sequencing and spatial profiling workflows.</p>

<p>Before his time in industry, Chao worked at the Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia (CHOP) and the University of Pennsylvania, where he contributed to high-impact studies in immunology, cancer biology, infectious diseases, and neurodegeneration. 
His toolkit spans cutting-edge transcriptomics and proteomics platforms including XLIP-Seq, 4sU-Seq, ChIP-Seq, scRNA-Seq, CyTOF, and Olink — all supported by deep experience in pipeline development with Snakemake, Nextflow, Python, R, and cloud/HPC environments.
Earlier in his career, he helped build CLIPdb and contributed to foundational ENCODE efforts on RNA-binding proteins and long non-coding RNAs.</p>

<p>Chao is passionate about applying data science and engineering to tackle big data challenges in biomedical research. He thrives at the intersection of biology and computation, building scalable pipelines and analytical frameworks to extract insights from single-cell, spatial, and multi-omics datasets. At CNH, he’s excited to collaborate across teams to transform complex data into actionable discoveries for pediatric care.</p>

<p>We’re thrilled to have Chao on board as we continue building a robust analytical infrastructure to drive discovery and precision medicine in pediatric brain tumor research here at Children’s.
Welcome, Chao! 👏</p>]]></content><author><name>Jo Lynne Rokita</name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to welcome Dr. Chao Di as a Senior Bioinformatics Engineer and Scientist in the Rokita Lab and the Brain Tumor Institute Bioinformatics Core at Children’s National Hospital (CNH) 🎉.]]></summary></entry></feed>