<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/preview/pr-9/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/preview/pr-9/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-12-26T18:58:17+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-9/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Rokita Lab</title><entry><title type="html">Rokita Lab opens at Children’s National Hospital</title><link href="/preview/pr-9/2024/10/28/lab-opening.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rokita Lab opens at Children’s National Hospital" /><published>2024-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-26T18:55:24+00:00</updated><id>/preview/pr-9/2024/10/28/lab-opening</id><content type="html" xml:base="/preview/pr-9/2024/10/28/lab-opening.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are thrilled to announce the opening of the Rokita Lab at Children’s National within the Brain Tumor Institute (BTI) and Center for Cancer and Immunology Research (CCIR)! 
Situated in a leading pediatric institution, our lab is equipped with cutting-edge technology and resources, fostering a collaborative environment for groundbreaking discoveries. 
We’re excited to accelerate our research and expand our efforts to improve outcomes for children with brain cancer.</p>

<p>We are immediately hiring bioinformatics scientists to join our lab!</p>]]></content><author><name>jolynne-rokita</name></author><category term="lab" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are thrilled to announce the opening of the Rokita Lab at Children’s National within the Brain Tumor Institute (BTI) and Center for Cancer and Immunology Research (CCIR)! Situated in a leading pediatric institution, our lab is equipped with cutting-edge technology and resources, fostering a collaborative environment for groundbreaking discoveries. We’re excited to accelerate our research and expand our efforts to improve outcomes for children with brain cancer.]]></summary></entry></feed>